字幕来源：殇 @豆瓣  陀螺凡达可 @豆瓣
■
后期：折翼的乌鸦儿
不用担心
Don't worry about it.
我第一天干活的时候
On-- on my first day,
就把他们在课上教的东西全忘了
I forgot everything that they taught me in those classes.
-真的吗  -是啊
-Really?  -Yeah.
第一天总会有点棘手
I mean, day one's always a little tough.
你也知道  不管当时训练进行如何
It's like, you know, no matter how the training goes,
最后总会有无法预料的情况
there's-- there's always room for something
会出漏子
that's just totally unpredictable.
对了
Oh, I--
要是你准备好的话  我有个相当好的故事讲给你听
I've got a pretty good story for you if you're ready for it.
-好啊  -早上好
-OK.  -Hey, what's up?
-早上好  -你们见过面了么
-Hey.  -Did you guys meet?
还没呢  我是奈特
No. Nate.
你好
Hi.
-你好  -我是杰西卡
-Hey!  -Jessica.
好啦  都听我讲
OK, listen up.
当时我是第一周来上班  还是负责看门的
So it's like my first week on the job, and I'm at gate duty, right?
什么是看门的
What's that?
如果有孩子想要离开  按法律来说我们并不能阻止
If a kid wants to leave, legally we can't stop them,
所以我们安排人在门口守着尝试劝阻他们
so we put someone at the gate to try and talk them out of it.
-你来得可真快  -那还用说
-Whoa, you got here quick.  -I did.
-早上好  -你好
-Good morning.  -Hi.
奈特  这是格蕾丝  她是你的新上司
Nate, this is Grace. She's your new boss.
-你好  -你好
-Hello.  -Hey.
-认识你很高兴  -认识你很高兴
-Hi, nice to meet you.  -Nice to meet you.
我要是你就不会戴那条领带
I would lose the tie if I were you.
而且如果你在听梅森讲故事的话
And if you're listening to a story of Mason's,
可要注意他基本都是在胡说八道
understand that there's very little reality in it.
别败了大伙的兴头好么
Hey, don't piss in the water before we put our toes in.
事实上这听起来还蛮中肯的
It actually feels pretty mellow.
好啦  所以作为我美妙的新上司
OK, so Grace, my wonderful new boss at the time,
格蕾丝当时就安排我看了三小时的门
she leaves me at my gate duty
期间还一次厕所都不给我上
for like three hours without a bathroom break.
何况我当时还吃了他们这做的玉米饼
And I'm dying because I ate the tacos
肚子疼得都快挂了
that they serve here,
而且她还没告诉我那些玉米饼是出了名的泻药
and she failed to tell me that they're a known laxative.
然后一个比我还高一英寸  体型高大的
So this kid, 16 years old, this big fuckin' intimidating dude,
十六岁男孩朝着我走来
he's like a foot taller than me.
大摇大摆地就走出了门口
He walks up and he just cruises out the gate.
那才是我第二天上班  所以根本不知道发生了什么事情
It's my second day, so I don't know what the hell is going on.
不过格蕾丝当时就站在那眼睁睁地就让他走掉了
But Grace, she's standing right there, and she just lets it happen.
就听他瞎说吧
Whatever.
反正当时我就看到梅森就在那儿默默坐着
What I saw was Mason just sitting there
而韦斯利正从门的另外一侧对我微笑
and Wesley smiling at me from the opposite side of the gate
他也知道我们没有办法干涉他
because he knows that we can't touch him.
为什么呢
Why not?
他们一旦出了大门我们就没法管他们了
Once they're a foot outside the gate, we can't touch them.
所以格蕾丝就叫我去跟着他  我照着指示跟了几个小时
So Grace tells me to follow him, so I do for hours,
跟在他身后大概两三米
just walking eight feet behind him.
最后他上了一辆公交车 我也跟着上去
Eventually he gets on this bus, so I get on the bus too.
这时候我大脑一片空白  唯一能想到的是
And at this point I can't think of anything
那些玉米饼如何把我的肚子闹得天翻地覆
but whatever the hell these tacos are doing to my bowels.
所以我下了个决心  滚你妈的
So I make up my mind, fuck this.
我下一站就一定得下车
I've got to get off at the next stop
不然我铁定就得在大庭广众下拉裤子了
or I'm going to lose it in my shorts in front of all these people.
而正巧在我作出这一决定时
And exactly as I make this decision,
韦斯利从过道另一侧扭过他那硕大无朋的脑袋
Wesley leans his big-ass head over to me from across the aisle,
用非常冷峻的神情对我说
and he says, really calm,
"我下一站下车  如果你再跟着我"
I'm getting off at the next stop, and if you do too,
"我他妈就把你老二揪下来然后塞回你嘴里"
I'm going to rip your fuckin' balls off and feed them to you.
我的妈呀  可别忘了我的警告
Holy shit. Remember what I said.
拜托这部分可是真的  我当时真的就在那儿
Hey now, this part is true. I was there.
-真的么  -恩
-Really?  -Mm-hmm.
-你真的确定  -是的
-Are you sure?  -Yeah.
然后公交车就停了  韦斯利下了车
So the bus stops. He gets off.
我等了一会
I wait a second.
就往车门走  但他就在车门
I go over to the door, but he's just standing there
几米开外的人行道上站着
on the sidewalk like 10 feet away,
双眼直直地盯着我  等着我下车
staring at me, waiting.
可我还能怎么办  我又没有别的办法
What can I do? I have no other choice.
于是我还是下了车
So I step off the bus.
而就在那瞬间我一直紧绷的肛门终于坚持不住了
And the second that my feet touch the ground,
我肚子像炸开了花儿一样
it is like a knot in my asshole untied,
里面的东西就顺着我的腿往下流
and the fiesta in my stomach just comes pouring down my legs.
于是我就站在那  由着大便在我腿上奔流
So I'm just standing there, shit gushing down my thighs.
我他妈还把最爱的那双耐克给毁了
I ruined my fuckin' favorite Nikes.
然后韦斯利就在边上笑得头都要碰到地上了
And Wesley is just there, doubled over, losing it.
他笑起来那种阵势  他妈的我这辈子可还没见
And he's fuckin' laughing so hard. I've never seen anything--
-奈特快来  -等会儿  咋了
-Here we go, Nate.  -Wait, what?
-来啊奈特  -快去
-Come on, Nate!  -Go
萨米
Sammy!
-悠着点  -好啦好啦
-Hey, hey, hey, hey!  -Hey.
-我抓到他啦  -你们这些变态  他妈快放我走
-Whoa, I got him.  -Let go, you fucking perverts!
-好的  -奈特  麻烦帮忙抓住他的脚
-OK.  -Nate, grab his feet, please.
我们就在这草地上坐一会  等你冷静下来
Just going to sit down here in the grass for a while until you de-escalate.
冷静下来  你妹啊操你鸭
De-escalate my asshole, you duck fuckers!
我不太特别确定操你鸭是什么意思
I'm not quite sure what you mean by that.
你也知道这种情况的  萨米  等着发作期过去就好
You know the drill, Sammy. Just let it pass.
伙计你还好吧
You all right, buddy?
他这次跑得还挺远  我觉得好像还破了新纪录
Whoa, he got pretty far that time. I think it's a new record.
所以话说回来  最后他决定跟我一起回来
So anyway, after all that he ends up coming back with me,
因为他实在忍不住自己去告诉大家
but only because he's so excited to tell everyone in our unit
我拉了裤子这件糗事的心情
that I pooped my pants.
而且他的确这么做了  他告诉了所有人
And he does. He tells everyone.
而且不知道怎么回事居然还被我妈听到了
Somehow it even got back to my mom.
萨米  你也听过这个故事对吧
You heard that story, right Sammy?
没错
Yeah.
-你们还好吧  -好极了
-How are you guys doing over there?  -Fantastic.
萨米你感觉怎样  都发泄出来了么
How are you feeling, Sammy? You got it all out?
想去休息下么
You want to go take a nap?
好  那咱们起来吧
All right, let's get you up.
走吧
Up we go, bud.
好啦  我们办公室见吧
All right, I'll see you back at the office.
-自己当心  -好吧
-Look into yourself, man.  -All right.
这家伙肯定是早上吃足了谷物麦片
This guy's been eating his Wheaties in the morning.
话说萨米你想过去参加奥运会么
Have you ever thought about the Olympics, Sammy?
跑跑田径赛什么的
Running track?
如果你想了解下这些孩子都经历过什么
These are the files on our kids, if you want to see
这里这些是关于他们的文档
what kind of crap they've been through.
他们在这要待多久
How long do they stay here?
通常来说不到一年  不过我们这有几位
Supposedly less than a year, but we have a few hat
已经待了三年多了
have been here a little over three.
在郡里面决定他们之后该怎么办之前
We just keep them
我们就一直在这收容他们
until the county figures out where they're going to go next.
汤姆
Tom!
快去刷牙
Go brush your teeth!
记住了  你既不是他们的家长也不是他们的治疗师
Remember, you are not their parent. You are not their therapist.
你来这唯一的目的  就是为他们提供一个安全的环境
You are here to create a safe environment, and that's it.
了解
Got it.
另外既然你是新人  他们会考验和测试你
And since you're new, they're going to try and test you,
看看你好不好对付
see what they can get away with.
所以最好暂时对他们的要求一律拒绝
So just say no for a while.
拒绝  好吧
No. OK.
在成为他们朋友前  你大概要先学会唱黑脸才行
Kind of got to be an asshole before you can be their friend.
不过不用紧张
You're going to be fine.
五分钟之后开始社区会议
Community meeting is in five minutes!
-路易斯  你最好乖乖起床  -可我不想
-Luis, you better be up.  -Ugh, I don't want to be.
所以这就是我不起床的下场么
So this is how it's going to be?
你有五秒钟的时间
You've got five seconds.
我操
Fuck!
路易斯
Luis!
我也爱你
I love you too.
这可一点也不好玩
It's not cool.
坎德拉  你愿意做今天的会议记录么
Kendra, will you be secretary for us today?
我想没问题吧
Sure, I guess.
好的  谢谢
OK, thank you.
社区会议现在开始
Community meeting is now in session.
有什么新通告么
Community announcements?
什么都没有吗
No announcements?
怎么啦  伙计们
What's going on, you guys?
怎么都看上去死气沉沉的
You look a little dead.
-你都把他们怎么了  -我也不知道
-What did you do to them?  -I don't know.
我在外面放了个屁
I farted when I was outside.
大概是有些气体跟着我一起飘了进来
Maybe some of it followed me in.
所以你又拉裤子了么
Did you shart yourself again?
谢谢你啊路易斯  不过我没拉裤子
No, Luis, I did not shart, thank you very much.
而且那件事就只发生过一次  当时你都还没来这呢
And that happened one time, and you weren't even here yet, so.
-还是很好笑嘛  -好啦我们说完了么
-It's still funny.  -OK, are we done?
我今天光这故事都听三遍了
I've-- I've heard that story like three times today.
-没办法  谁叫这是个好故事  -确实没错
-Yeah, but it's a good story.  -It is a good story.
好啦  如果没有人想讲个跟大号无关的事情
OK, if no one has any non-poop related announcements,
我这有一个
I have one.
正如你们大部分人都知道的  马库斯马上就要18岁
As most of you are already aware, Marcus is turning 18
得离开我们了
and will be leaving us.
我可以住他房间么
Can I have his room?
我们下周将给他举办一个小小的派对
We are going to be throwing him a little party next week.
马库斯  你有什么要求么
Marcus, any requests?
我能把我的头剃了么
Can I shave my head?
我指的是派对上想吃点啥
I was talking about food for the party.
不不  我没什么想吃的
No, I don't. I don't want food.
我就想剃个头
I want to shave my head.
好吧  只要拿着剃刀的是我  那就没问题
OK. As long as I hold the razor.
行
Cool.
其他人  有什么想法么
OK, everyone else, thoughts?
马库斯派对上我们该吃点啥
Food for Marcus' party, what are we going to do?
好啦  好啦
OK, OK.
麻烦大家一个一个说
Everyone, one at a time, please.
谢谢路易斯还举了手
Luis, thank you for raising your hand.
那边那个怪胎是谁
Who's the weird guy over there?
那是奈特
Oh, that is Nate.
拜托不要让他难堪  这可是人家第一天来
Please do not be jerks to him. It is his first day.
-你想来点自我介绍么  -好啊
-Do you want to introduce yourself?  -Um, sure.
好的
Yeah.
大家好
Hey.
你们已知道  我叫做奈特
Uh, as you know, my name's Nate.
我  我刚刚
And, uh, I just--
停了一年学校的课  想着可以
I took a year off of school because, you know,
出来收获一些社会经验
I just wanted to get some life experience.
而且我一直就很希望能照顾下社会底层的孩子们
And I always wanted to work with underprivileged kids.
你他妈的什么意思啊
Hey, what the fuck is that supposed to mean?
冷静点  马库斯
Marcus, settle down.
我没事  就想知道你说那句话是什么意思
No, I want to know what you mean by that,
"社会底层"
"underprivileged."
我并不是那个意思
That's not what I meant.
那么说话前先他妈想清楚
Then think about your fucking words before you speak!
-你个菜逼  -你被降级了
-Newbie!  -Hey! That's a level drop.
回你自己房间去
Go to your room.
快点回去
对不住了兄弟
Sorry, man.
真的不好意思
Sorry.
级别和情绪  你们都了解规矩的
Um, levels and feelings, you know the drill.
路易斯开个头吧
Let's start with you, Luis.
绿色  还成
Green. Fine.
银色  一般般
Silver. Whatever.
黄色  感觉不大对劲
Yellow. I feel funny.
绿色  都还不错
Green. All right.
黄色  有点烦
Yellow. Annoyed.
12号收容所  我是格蕾丝
Short Term 12, this is Grace.
这会就来
Right now?
所以你觉得怎么样
So what do you think?
-什么  -我的新台灯
-Hmm?  -The new lamp.
还怪好玩儿的
It's really a trip.
你触摸金属部分就能开关
You can turn it on and off by touching the metal part.
试试看呗
Try it.
-有意思吧  -是的
-Cool, huh?  -Hmm.
话说我要去参加一个小组会议
Look, I'm supposed to be in a group session like right now.
你介意我们边走边聊么
You mind if we walk and talk?
不介意
No.
这是贾登
This is Jayden.
她今早刚被安排给我们
She just got appointed to us this morning.
她爸爸是我朋友的一个朋友  人很好  很有文化
Her father's a friend of a friend, real nice guy, very cultured.
那她为什么不跟她爸一起住
Why isn't she with him?
他妻子前几年去世了
Oh, he lost his wife a few years back.
后来贾登就没给她爸爸好日子过
Jayden hasn't made life very easy on him.
她在几个收容所进进出出好几回了
For the past couple of years,
都是因为危险行为
she's been in and out of group homes for dangerous behavior.
上周她还咬了自己治疗师的鼻子
Last week she bit her therapist's nose.
真棒
Great.
没错  所以我们将在工作日收容她
Yeah, so we'll have her during the week,
不过她周末能回家
but she gets weekend home visits.
好的
All right.
我告诉她爸我们会照顾好她的
I told her father we'd take good care of her.
-我一向都照顾好所有人  -我知道
-I take good care of everyone.  -I know you do.
这也是为什么我相信你也会照顾好贾登
That's why I'm trusting you to do the same with Jayden.
-她什么时候到这呢  -说不定这会儿已经到了
-When does she get here?  -She might be here already.
我喜欢你的名字  贾登
I like your name, Jayden.
这是个男生的名字
It's a boy's name.
真的么
Really?
我不觉得
I don't think so.
威尔・史密斯
Will Smith
是这么觉得的（威尔・史密斯的儿子也叫贾登）
did.
听着  这些东西你不能留在房间里
OK, well, these things you can't keep in your room,
我们会帮你保管  就放在外面的柜子里
but we'll keep them in the closet out here,
想用就尽管来拿
and you can check them out whenever you want them.
行了  我知道规矩的
Yep, I know the rules.
不准有皮带  不准有剃刀  不准有剪刀
No belts, no razors, no scissors,
连自由也他妈的没有
no fuckin' freedom.
-不准说脏话  -妈的我居然忘了这条
-No cussing.  -Shit, I forgot about that one.
刚才这句这么狡猾我就放过你了
I'm going to let that one slip because it was clever.
好了  走吧  去看看你的房间
All right. Let's go see your room.
就是这啦
Here it is.
还真诱人
Wow, it's so inviting.
你在墙上挂什么都没关系  只要内容合适就行
You can put whatever you want on the walls as long as it's appropriate.
所以阴茎的照片也不行
So no pictures of penises?
除非是科普性质的
Not unless it's very scientific.
看起来真棒
Oh, wow. This is really cool.
才没呢  都是乱画的狗屎
No, that's crap.
这你都能叫狗屎  我真妒忌你
If you call that crap, I'm jealous.
上床前你要是把脏衣服挂在外头的话
If you put your clothes outside the door before bedtime,
值夜班的人会来帮忙清洗
the overnighters will wash them.
还有  门不能关上
And, um, you can't keep your door closest.
我现在已经不会那么做了
I don't do that anymore.
我并没有说你会这么做
I'm not saying that you do.
我的意思是我真要想自残的话
I mean, even if I ever did want to cut myself,
这扇门就算是他妈开着的也没法阻止我
keeping the fuckin' door cracked isn't going to stop me.
我可已经警告过你别说脏话了
I already warned you about cussing.
那句话可要被算作降级
That one's going to be a level drop.
天啊被降级了呢  我可该怎么办好啊
Oh no, a level drop. What am I going to do?
你这种态度对我们谁都不好
Your attitude is not helping either one of us.
-话说那家伙怎么了  -哪个家伙
-Hey, what happened to that guy?  -What guy?
那个害你拉裤子的大个子家伙
The big kid that made you poop your pants.
-韦斯利  -对
-Wesley.  -Yeah.
他之后又逃跑了
He ran away again,
结果两天之后有人在灌木丛里发现了他的尸体
and then two days later someone found him dead in the bushes.
什么
What?
这才是这个故事真正的结局
That is the real ending to the story.
我不喜欢这部分
I don't like that part.
-亲爱的一起走吗  -我得去清醒下头脑
-Sugar, coming with me?  -I'm going to clear my head.
奈特  第一天你干得还不错嘛  谢谢
That was a good first day, Nate. Thank you.
回见
See ya.
那好  兄弟
All right, man.
-保重  -行
-Yeah, take it easy.  -All right.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
你是格蕾丝吗
Grace?
进来吧  亲爱的
Come on in, Hon.
测试结果出来的确是阳性的
So the test did come back positive.
太好了
Lovely.
你现在感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
我自己在家已经做过大概七八次测试了
I already did, like, seven of those tests at home,
所以并不会太惊讶
so I'm not really surprised.
好  那接下来你有这么几个选择
OK, well, you have a few options to explore.
我们可以一起梳理一下
And we can go over it for--
不如就预约周六的检查
We can just make an appointment for Saturday.
你不想听听看其它选择么
You don't want to hear the other options?
不用了
Uh-uh.
行
OK.
你以前怀孕过么
Have you ever been pregnant before?
怀过一次
One time.
好
OK.
懒虫  怎么这么久才回来
Hey, stinker, what took you so long?
别这样
Oh, no.
我不知道你原来还留着那顶蠢兮兮的帽子
I didn't know you still had that stupid hat.
这顶蠢兮兮的帽子我可是留定了
I will always have this stupid hat.
你这在干嘛呢
What's going on in here?
既然你跟单车偷情去了
Well, since you were out cheating on me with your bike,
我决定给自己做一点墨西哥菜
I decided I'd make myself some chiles rellenos,
酿辣椒  玉米饼  还有我妈最爱的番茄辣酱
homemade tortillas, and my mom's famous salsa.
看起来我们两个人吃也够了
Looks like there's enough for two.
好吧  我可不这么觉得
All right. I doubt it.
梅斯  你可没必要嫉妒弗洛伊德
Mase, you don't have to be jealous of Floyd.
弗洛伊德  你的单车现在还有名字啦
Floyd? Your bike has a name now?
那还用说  我们关系可好了
Of course he does. We're very close.
我搞不懂他有什么好的
I don't know what you see in him.
摸起来很顺滑
Mmm. Nice grip.
坐上去很舒服
Comfy seat.
怎么可能比我的还要舒服
There is no way his seat is as comfy as mine.
这倒没错
You're right.
我先去洗个澡好了
I think I'm going to go take a shower.
弗洛伊德可是让我大汗淋漓
Floyd got me all sweaty.
我恨死那部单车了
I hate that bike!
操你妈的  弗洛伊德
Fuck you, Floyd.
好啦  我的搞定了
OK, I'm done with mine.
好啦
On, yeah.
马上就好
OK, yep. Almost there.
你这是在最后关头乱涂乱画吧
Those are some crazy last-minute changes you're making.
差不多吧  我鼻子画的太烂了
Yeah, well, I really suck at noses.
好吧  你先来
OK, you go first.
我勒个去
Aw, damn it.
你永远画得这么好
Yours are always so good.
谢谢
Thanks.
不过我看起来好像流浪汉
I look like a homeless guy, though.
你本来看起来就像流浪汉
You do kind of look like a homeless guy.
谢谢  我脸上那是啥
Oh yeah, thank you. What's that on my face there?
-这个吗  -是的
-Oh, that?  -Yep.
那是你胡子上残留的一小片鳄梨
Well, that's the piece of avocado that's in your beard.
-不是吧  -真就是的
-No.  -Yes.
-卧槽  -我说吧
-Oh, fuck.  -Yes.
-它从头到尾可一直待在那儿  -喔
-It's been there the whole time.  -Ooh, yeah.
所以画出来的效果才这么好
So now you're all nicely painted.
提醒得真及时  谢谢你
Thank you for saying something-- sooner
确实很及时  只是
I did. I just--
好啦  来看一眼我的
OK. Um, all right, here we go.
平复好你的心情  不然你是会被惊呆的
Just take it easy, OK, because you're going to freak out when you see this.
我觉得这是我目前为止最了不起的作品
I think it might be my best one yet.
好吧
OK.
点评下嘛
Hmm? Come on.
你他妈可不能小瞧这幅画
You can't fuck with that.
我确实他妈的不能小瞧这幅画
I can't fuck with that.
-这鼻子画得也太精彩了  -是的
-That nose is amazing.  -Yeah.
我大概是照着蘑菇形状画的
And I was going for kind of a mushroomy thing in there.
那是胡子么
Is that a beard?
不是  我只是
No. I was, uh--
我只是想制造些阴影而已  我觉得还挺好看
I was trying to shade. I think it looks pretty cool.
确实挺好看
Yeah, it looks very cool.
不过我头上长出来的是啥
What's growing out of my head?
你在问这些东西么  这是花
Oh, these? Flowers.
他们代表了你那美丽的脑袋里种种奇思妙想
They represent the peculiar thoughts that grow out of your gorgeous mind.
你为什么要对我这么好
Why are you so nice to me?
你这会儿是认真的么
You being serious now?
好吧  这很简单
Well, it's easy.
因为你是我这一生中见过的最怪胎
It's because you are the weirdest,
又最美丽的人
most beautiful person that I've ever met in my whole entire life.
没啥
Um. Nothing.
只是你好久没有这么热情地亲我了
It's just been a long time since you kissed me like that.
又在说大话
That's not true.
我们已经九天又十三个小时没有做爱了
Well, we haven't had sex in 9 days and 13 hours.
还精确到小时是吧
Down to the hour, huh?
我做错了什么吗
Did I do something?
没有
No.
你棒极了
You're wonderful.
那是怎么回事
What is it, then?
你总得让我了解你在想些什么吧
Please, you have to let me in your head once in a while
不然我在这都快要担心疯了  好么
or I'm just going to go nuts, OK?
你这么做都是为我么
Are you doing this just for me?
你还好吧
You OK?
-还好  -那好
-Yes.  -Yeah?
你需要我停下来么
You don't want me to stop?
-停下来  -为什么
-Stop.  -Why?
-快停下来  -喔
-Stop!  -Ow!
卧槽
Shit.
又咋了格蕾丝
What the hell, Grace?
好啦大伙们
OK, everyone.
我知道你们大部分人都见过她了
I think most of you have already met her,
不过还是要说明下我们社区有新成员加入了
but we have anew member of our community.
贾登  你想自我介绍下么
Jayden, would you introduce yourself?
请不要被我的不友好冒犯
Please don't be offended if I'm not very friendly,
不过我很快就要回去跟我爸住了
but I'm going to be living with my dad soon,
所以我并不想在短期的友谊上浪费时间
and I don't really like wasting time on short-term relationships.
不是刻意针对你们其中的谁
So, you know, it's nothing personal.
她看上去真是非常友好
She seems like a really nice girl.
我相信我们大家都能尊重她的私人意愿  是吧
Hey, I think we all can respect her space, OK?
大家今天想玩些什么
OK, what do we want to play for rec today?
威浮球
Wiffle ball, dude!
-好  -得了吧  伙计
-OK.  -No, man.
你永远都在玩那么幼稚的游戏
You're always playing that stupid game.
那是因为你怎么玩都这么烂吧
Because you always suck at it.
除非你技术变好了  等到那时再考虑别的吧
Until you get good at it, maybe we could stop playing it.
-嘴别太贱了啊伙计  -你们俩都够了
-Watch your mouth, bro.  -Both of you, cut it out.
别人还有什么意见么
Any other suggestions?
萨米你说
Yes, Sammy?
我们可以玩大家伙与小家伙么
Can we play Big and Small?
这是个真正存在的游戏  还是你刚刚编出来的
Is that a real game, or is that a game you just made up?
这是个我刚刚编出来的真正存在的游戏
It's a real game that I just made up.
好吧
OK.
那也许你等会儿可以把规则解释给我听
Well, maybe you can explain that to me later.
排成一行  伙计们
Straight line, guys.
我先去查下房  等会见
I'm going to do room checks, so I'll meet you.
好的
Oh, OK.
纳斯  你好
Hi, Nas.
大家加油
Come on, guys.
加油  桑塔  加油
Let's go, Shawnta, let's go!
我们来玩儿棒球吧
All right, we got a baseball game.
来吧  你们能行的
There you go. You got this.
萨米  萨米
Sammy. Hey, yo, Sammy.
-快去捡球  -快跑丫头  快跑
-Get-- get the ball!  -Run, girl, run!
走啊  萨米
Come on, Sammy!
这游戏对你来说太幼稚了么
You too good for this game?
什么
What?
威浮球对你来说太幼稚了么
Too good for wiffle ball?
我不喜欢出汗的感觉
I don't like sweat.
话说康纳  你走过来点
Hey, you know what, Connor? Just come-- just come closer.
马库斯来了  他肯定又打不中球
It's Marcus. He ain't going to hit it.
你确定你不用拿一根粗点的球棒么
You sure you don't want to get the fat bat?
真的吗
No?
看到了吧  一阵
Strike one, everybody.
一阵了
Strike one.
-这可不算数  -这可是刚好投到位啊拜托
-That wasn't no strike.  -That was right down the middle.
这可是大联盟的规则  你没办法遵守么
This is the big leagues, boy. You can't handle it?
你就继续吹牛吧
Better keep flapping them gums.
你可以来陪我们跳大绳么
Hey. You want to jump rope with us?
我猜不可以
No?
不好意思
Sorry.
我们不能陪你们
We're not supposed to.
我们说的可不是这意思
That's not what we meant.
我也能一起听么
Can I hear?
三振了  出局了换人吧
Strike three. Change it up.
我猜你妈下周能见到你肯定很高兴吧
Bet your ma is real excited to see you next week, huh?
-马库斯  -你他妈说啥
-Marcus!  -What the fuck?
你这个贱逼  你刚才他妈说我妈啥
What the fuck did you about my mama, you little bitch?
你想干什么
What are you doing?
快给我滚去长椅那儿
Get your ass over to the bench.
行啦行啦  大家来帮忙把路易斯抬走吧
Come on, come on. Guys, get Luis out of here.
马库斯还好吧  你行么
Is Marcus OK? You good?
行了我来吧  我们走吧路易斯
Yeah, I got it. Luis, come on.
小心点
Come on.
你身上  哪里疼
OK, where-- where where-- where does it hurt?
来吧  在这坐下
Come on. Come on, sit over here.
我们就在这休息会儿  好么
We're going to sit down for a little while, OK?
你还好吧伙计  你感觉怎么样
You OK, man? How do you feel?
感觉很糟  这简直就疯了吧
Not good. I mean, that-- that was crazy.
他们真就这么野蛮地打架么
They just fight like that?
奈特我可没在问你感觉怎么样
Nate, I'm not asking you how you're feeling.
是的
Right.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你还好吧
How are you?
你得跟我坦白都发生了什么事
You need to tell me what the hell is going on.
暴力加上藏毒
Assault and drug possession.
你知道这就够你去蹲少管所了吧
You realize that's enough to get your ass thrown in juvie.
你觉得我他妈真的在乎么
Do you think I give a fuck?
你还有一周就可以离开这里了
You're out of here in less than a week.
你太聪明了  远远不该被困在这儿
You're so much smarter than this.
-我知道外面的世界很凶险  -我他妈什么都不怕
-I know it's scary out there.  -I ain't scared of shit.
其实我想说的是你真的不会想
All I'm saying is, getting thrown in jail is not
被扔进监狱的
what you want to do.
我爸在那儿被关了十年
My dad has been in there for 10 years.
我不想你也遭遇这种事
I don't want that for you.
直接回你房间
Straight to your room.
房间打扫完之前可没有自由活动
No free time untilall your chores are done.
他这又是怎么了
What's going on with him?
他只是不想离开罢了
He doesn't want to leave.
我该找他聊一下么
Should I go talk to him?
好吧  那我就这样乖乖进去等马库斯
All right, I'll just be inside
把我揍个屁滚尿流
letting Marcus kick the shit out of me.
玩得开心点
Have fun.
你有什么新歌词想让我试听一下么
You got some new lyrics you want to try out on me?
里面可是很多脏话
There's a lot of fucks in it.
我不会告密的
I won't tell.
大概这样就行
Mm-hmm. Those are pretty much it.
-节奏比较慢  -好吧  我来试试
It's slow. All right, let's see.
我来试试看
Let's see here.
这样行么
Like that?
开始了
Yeah. All right.
临近十八岁一切都不再重要
It don't matter, now, damn near 18.
我脑海里的一切美好都他妈的已经消散
All the pretty pictures in my fuckin' head is faded.
一想到生养我那家伙就周身不爽
And when I think about that trick that raised me,
那婊子她可真的会犯神经
I thinkabout sick, because the bitch is crazy.
臭婊子你给我滚蛋  伤痛也都统统滚蛋
Fuck that bitch, nigga, fuck that pain.
我神志紊乱但你却还填满我的脑海
Your body's in a ditch inside this turned up brain.
我说你怎还好意思  好意思当妈
I mean, I can't see how you claim it, you being ma?
医生们反应敏锐从坑蒙拐骗中将我救走
Doctors snatched me out the snatch of pure evil with eagle claws.
你个贱货  带着你的生活给我滚蛋
Ho, ho, ho, slut, fuck the way you want it.
让你低能的小儿子捕鸽求生
Got your young, dumb son pitching pigeons for money.
天气再好也冰冷刺骨
I mean, it's colder than the bitch when it's sunny.
屡次三番扑灭我的热情
Blows raining down on the glow.
真的还敢声张你仍爱我
Got the nerve to tell me you love me?
我说  又来
I said, again?
又来
Again?
又来这套说辞
Sell it again?
臭婊子我可才十岁
Bitch, I'm 10.
让我出去结交朋友
Let me go outside and function with friends.
你称你是妈妈  是母亲
You say you ma? You mother?
你他妈是女王吗
You the father-fucking queen?
我说好吧  我爱她  所以我尽弃前嫌
I say, all right, I love her so I flip it again.
没有下次了婊子  因为我比你坚强
No, not this time, bitch, because I'm stronger than you.
没有下次了婊子  我会比你更强
Not this time, bitch, swinging harder than you.
没有下次了婊子  我没有选择余地
No, not this time, bitch, you ain't leave me a choice.
我神志紊乱但你却还填满我的脑海
You just a body in a ditch in the brain of a boy.
临近十八一切都他妈糟透
All fucked up now, damn near 18.
往昔苦痛却都不会退却
All the pictures in my past ain't never fading.
总是心存幻想
I'm always wishing for something amazing,
但你人生如此混账哪还会有希望
but whenyour life is shit then it ain't no trading.
所以把我写到你的书里你才知道
So put me in your book so you know what it's like
不知道正常生活是什么样的滋味
to live a life not knowing what a normal life's like.
所以为我贴个标签你才知道
Put a label on my head so you know what it's like
不知道正常生活是什么样的滋味
to live alife not knowing what a normal life's like.
所以盯着我的双眼你才知道
Look into my eyes so you know what it's like.
Look into my eyes so you know what it's like to live a life
不知道正常生活是什么样的滋味.
not knowing what a normal life's like.
我  我不知道
Yeah, I-- I don't--
我不知道  不知道该说些什么了
I don't know what to say, man.
没关系
It's cool, man.
我就只想去剃个头
I just need to shave my head.
你觉得格蕾丝还会愿意来剃么
You think Grace will still shave it?
我喜欢你墙上的新装饰
I like the new wall decor.
谢谢  他们真的非常有启示性
Thanks. They're actually very informative.
我能跟你一起画画么
Can I draw with you?
当我九岁十岁时
When I was 9 or 10,
我会为我妈的男朋友们画肖像
I used to draw portraits of all my mom's boyfriends.
然后以一张十块钱的价格卖给他们
And then I'd sell them to her for $10 apiece.
你妈有多少男朋友
How many boyfriends did she have?
多到我最后存的钱都可以去买
Enough that I was able to save up
一台防摔的便携CD机
and buy one of those portable CD players with anti-shock protection.
-好古老的样子  -没关系
-You're old.  -Whatever.
其实还蛮有趣
Those things were cool.
你知道奇怪的是什么吗
You know what's weird?
当我给这些家伙画画的时候
Whenever I was drawing portraits of, you know, those guys,
我总是会花特别长的时间
I would always take forever.
光是描边就要用半个小时
30, 40 minutes just stringing them along, saying,
还一边说着自己要多加点阴影
oh, I've just got to do a couple more shadows,
或者再修改下鼻子什么的
or, I'm just fixing the nose.
我也不知道为什么
I don't know why I did that.
我真的讨厌他们每一个人
I hated every single one of them.
或许你只是试图把他们从你妈身边支开吧
Maybe you were just trying to keep them away from your mom.
或许吧
Maybe.
你搞定了么
-Are you done?
差不多了  只需要再加点阴影  再修改下鼻子就好
Almost. I've just got to add a few shadows and fix the nose a little.
你可还真他妈聪明啊
You are such a smartass.
你也被降级了
That's a level drop.
哦不  千万别把我降级
Oh no, not a level drop.
我等会还想玩桌上足球
I wanted to play foosball later.
太可惜了
Oh, too bad.
好啦
OK.
搞定了
Finished.
想看眼么
You want to take a look?
马库斯  你看起来好极了
Looks great, Marcus.
你自己看一下
Check it out.
我头上还有包么
Is it lumpy?
什么意思
What do you mean?
我一般都留着长头发
I usually keep my hair long.
因为她总是爱打我的头
It's where she used to hit me at.
我头上现在还有包么
Is it still lumpy?
没事了兄弟
No way, man.
一点都看不出来
Not at all.
你自个儿瞧瞧吧
See for yourself.
摸起来还挺顺滑
Pretty smooth.
头后面呢
What about the back?
没有伤疤吗  没有
No scars? No--
什么都没有吗
no nothing?
看起来棒极了
It looks really great.
梅森
Mason.
什么
Hmm?
我有些事情想跟你说
I have something to tell you.
说吧
Yeah?
怎么了
What's up?
我们马上就要有宝宝了
We're going to have a baby.
什么
What?
我们马上就要有宝宝了
We're going to have a baby.
真的吗
We are?
真的
Mm-hmm.
好吧
OK.
等我一下
Uh, give me a minute.
我的天啊
Oh. boy!
卧槽
Holy shit.
你知道我们没问题的吧
You know we can do this, right?
因为我们将会成为一对了不起的父母
Because we are going to be some amazing parents.
你说是吧
OK?
我爱你格蕾丝
I love you so much, Grace.
爱你爱到都要失去理智了
So much it's insane.
给我看看
Let me see.
什么
Hmm?
还看不出来呢
You can't tell yet.
来嘛
Come on.
这感觉太奇妙了
That is so crazy.
-你听说萨米的事情了么  -怎么了
-Did you hear about Sammy?  -What?
昨晚他们把他的玩偶都拿走了
Last night they took all his dolls away.
他的治疗师把这叫做学会放手
His therapist is calling it a lesson in letting go.
都什么狗屁
Bullshit.
那些玩具都是他妹妹的吧
Those are all his sisters, right?
他还没准备好进行这一步
He's not ready for that.
该吃药了  萨米
It's time for your meds, Sammy.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry, bud.
贾登  来吃药
Jayden, meds.
-睡得怎么样  -糟透了
-How'd you sleep?  -Like crap.
告诉医生我需要吃更大剂量的
Can you tell the doctor I need a higher dosage of
曲唑酮（曲唑酮: 精神类药物有抗抑郁和镇静作用）
Trazodone?
好的  我会转告他
Mm-hmm, I will tell him.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
另外
And
你还能得到这个
it comes with this.
梅森做的
Mason made that.
谢啦
Thanks.
我听说你爸要来接你了
I heard your dad's picking you up.
是的
Yep.
你兴奋么
You excited?
没所谓啦
Whatever.
丹  前门有人
Dan, you have a visitor at the front gate.
在找你
Dan to the front gate.
去前门吧丹
The barber of Seville!
桑塔再见
Bye, Shawnta.
再见
Bye.
再见啦桑塔
Bye, Shawnta.
再见
Bye-bye.
一次性遭遇这么多鲨鱼可是非常
To encounter so many sharks can be--
这件事恰好发生在夏至前夜
The fact that this occurs
这一巧合不禁让我想到
on the eve of the summer solstice left me wondering.
妈的  你能帮忙看一下孩子么
Damn it. Will you watch the kids?
没问题
Sure.
奈特
Nate.
贾登
Jayden.
你知道你不能关门的
Come on, you know you can't keep the door closed.
别这么大力推门
Stop pushing on the door.
好啦  好啦  贾德
Hey. Hey, Jade.
你爸爸不能来我感到很抱歉
I'm really sorry about your dad.
-为什么她不能关门  -因为她割过腕
-Why can't she close her door?  -She's a cutter.
你个人渣我他妈能听到你在说啥
I can fucking hear you, dick!
说不定我这会儿就再割一次
Maybe I'll just cut myself right now,
这样你们就都失业了
and you'll all lose your fucking jobs!
别这样贾德
Come on, Jade.
别叫我贾德  你个臭婊子
Don't fucking call me Jade, you bitch!
贾登  麻烦冷静点吧  就把门打开好么
Jayden, come on. Please, just open the door.
如果你能把门打开  我们就不会烦你了
If you just open the door, then we won't bother you anymore.
如果你再不开门
If you're not going to open the door,
我们就只能使用武力了
then we're going to have to force it.
能帮帮忙么
Can you help me?
来吧  来吧
Yeah, yeah.
来吧
Yeah.
好了
OK.
都他妈滚出我的房间  你们这群他妈的
Get the fuck out of my room, you fucking--
别他妈碰我
stop touching me!
好了好了  都放轻松
All right, easy, easy, easy.
一二三  我们都坐下来
One, two, three, down.
操你妈
Ah, fuck you!
路易斯  坐下来
Luis, sit down.
你个肥猪都他妈要把我压扁了
You're fucking squishing me, you fatass!
对不起  现在好点了么
Sorry, how's that?
快放我走
Let me go!
-格蕾丝你不该待在这儿  -怎么了梅森
-You shouldn't be here, Grace.  -What's wrong, Mason?
你个臭傻逼软蛋搞不定我
Can't handle me for yourself, you weak-ass fuck?
还要这婊子来帮忙
Need the bitch to do it for you?
好好按着他  奈特
Hold her good, Nate.
没错  好好按着我奈特
Yeah, hold me good, Nate.
对不起
Sorry, man.
很快就会没事了贾登  很快就没事了
You're going to be OK, Jayden. It's going to be OK.
我恨你
I hate you.
我恨你们
这没关系
That's fine.
你现在用不着喜欢我
You don't have to like me right now.
等情绪过去了就好
Just let it pass.
你还好吧  奈特
How we doing, Nate?
不怎么好
Not so good.
你做得很好
You're doing good.
真的很好
You're doing really good.
格蕾丝  我的蛋糕好吃么
Grace, how's my cupcake?
这些古代岛屿都很寒冷
The ancient islands are cold.
-她还好吗  -我猜她这会儿正在发泄室里
-How is she?  -I guess she's in the cool-down room now.
把那递给我
I need that.
这里有大量的普通灰海豹
Common gray seals can be found here in abundance.
事实上  世界上有将近百分之四十的灰海豹
In fact, Scotland is home to 40% of the world's gray seal
都住在苏格兰
population.
大家每个人都拿一个
Everybody grab one.
都动起来
Come on.
想看看我的么
You want to see mine?
我的天
Shit.
那个是我打喷嚏的结果
That one's from a sneeze.
所以割错了地方  伤口特别深
Slipped and cut too deep.
我差点就把跟腱切断了
Almost cut my achilles.
为什么要这么做
Why?
我妈去世了
My mom died.
我就去跟我爸过
I went to live with my dad
只是当你内心在滴血时
and--it's impossible to worry about anything else
是没办法担心其它事的
when there's blood coming out of you.
妈的我真讨厌那玩意儿
God, I hate that thing.
我也是
Me too.
你想歇多久都随你
Take as much time as you need.
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you!
吹蜡烛  吹蜡烛
Blow them out! Blow them out!
快吹
Go!
贾登
Jayden!
大屁股大屁股
Ah, big booty, big booty, big booty!
大屁股呼叫四号
Big booty number four.
-四号收到呼叫五号  -五号收到呼叫六号
-Number four, number five.  -Number five, number six.
-六号收到呼叫五号  -五号收到呼叫十号
-Number six, number five.  -Number 5, number 10.
七号收到呼叫大屁股
Number seven, big booty.
大屁股收到呼叫十号
Big booty, number 10.
拜托  她还在这工作
Come on, she works here.
她真应该感到羞愧
She should be embarrassed.
我确实很羞愧
I am embarrassed.
好了没事  大家都会犯错
Hey, it's OK. It happens to all of us.
再来一轮怎么样
Let's go for another round Ready?
大屁股大屁股
Ah, big booty, big booty--
好了你们慢一点
Hmm, slow this down a little bit.
你们可一点节奏感都没有
Yo, y'all ain't got no rhythm, man.
确实没错
Tell me about it.
我已经很努力保持节奏感了
I'm trying to keep them in line.
可真的好难
It's just so hard.
梅斯  你对我亲如手足
Mase, I love you like a brother
但一旦要低调行事你就是我的耻辱
but I got tosay that when it come to being discreet, you're a disgrace.
他以为我们都不知道
I mean, he think we all don't know about him
他和格蕾丝偷偷约会的意图
and Grace on the low undercover trying to date.
我才不知道你在说些什么乱七八糟的东西
I don't know what you're talking about.
既然我是下一个
Uh, I'm out the gate, right?
大家都叫我奈特
My name is Nate.
初来乍到你们都把我吆喝
When I came here, y'all tried to player-hate.
大家都快坐下
Everyone sit down, please.
我们出现了一个擅自离开的情况
We have an AWOL.
贾登
Jayden!
-格蕾丝  -跟孩子们待在一起
-Grace!  -Stay with the kids!
我找到她就跟你打电话
I'll call you when I get her.
这种情况也是会发生的  不用担心
This happens. It's fine.
贾登
Jayden!
贾登  麻烦你走慢点好么
Jayden, can you slow down, please?
我觉得我快要吐了
I feel like I'm going to barf.
保持在安全距离外
Keep-- keep the same distance.
就这停下
Stop!
好的  好的
OK. OK.
你出门可就不能碰我了
You can't touch me outside of the grounds.
那我能跟你一块儿走么
Well, can I walk with you?
随你怎么走  但我绝对不会回去那儿了
Walk all you want, but I'm not going back there.
那就走吧
Let's walk, then.
贾登  你也知道你不该出现在这儿
Jayden, you know you're not supposed to be here.
我们现在在他爸爸家
Hey. Um, we're at her dad's house.
我不认为家里面有人但她还是进门了
I don't think that anyone's here, but she went in anyway.
好的  那谢谢了
OK, thanks.
他不在家么
He's not home?
你想回去么
Do you want to go back?
好吧
OK.
你还好么
You OK?
我们明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
我写了个故事  你想听听么
You want to hear a story I've been working on?
当然想啦
Of course.
这是个童话  所以里面都是些浅显的词语
Well, it's a kid's story, so there aren't any big words.
明白
OK.
很久很久以前  在大洋底下
Once upon a time, somewhere miles and miles
很深很深的地方
beneath the surface of the ocean,
住着一只小章鱼  她的名字叫妮娜
there lived a young octopus named Nina.
妮娜每天大部分时间都在用岩石和贝壳
Nina spent most of her time alone making strange creations
创作各种奇奇怪怪的东西  她非常开心
out of rocks and shells. And she was very happy.
但在某个星期一  一只鲨鱼突然出现了
But then on Monday the shark showed up.
鲨鱼问  "你叫什么名字"
"What's your name?" said the shark.
"妮娜"  她回答说
"Nina," she replied.
"你想做我的朋友么"  鲨鱼又问
"Do you want to be my friend?" he asked.
"好啊"
"OK.
"但我需要做些什么吗"  妮娜答到
What do I have to do?" said Nina.
"没什么了不得的"  鲨鱼接着说
"Not much," said the shark.
"就让我吃掉你的一只胳膊就好"
"Just let me eat one of your arms."
妮娜从来没有过朋友  所以她在疑惑
Nina had never had a friend before, so she wondered
要交上朋友是不是值得她这么做
if this was what you had to do to get one.
她低下头  看着自己的八条胳膊
She looked down at her eight arms and decided
心想即使少了一条也不会多糟
it wouldn't be so bad to give up one.
于是她就送了一只胳膊给她这位了不起的新伙伴
So she donated an arm to her wonderful new friend.
那个星期后的每一天  妮娜和鲨鱼都会一起玩儿
Every day that week, Nina and the shark would play together.
他们一起探索洞穴  一起堆砌沙堡
They explored caves, built castles of sand,
一起游得飞快飞快
and swamreally, really fast.
然后每天晚上鲨鱼都会饿肚子
And every night the shark would be hungry,
妮娜就会递给他另外一只胳膊
and Nina would give him another one of her arms to eat.
一直到星期天  在玩了一整天后鲨鱼又告诉妮娜
On Sunday, after playing all day, the shark told Nina
他感觉很饿
that he was very hungry.
"我不明白"  她说
"I don't understand," she said.
"我已经给了你六只胳膊  你怎么还想再要一只"
"I've already given you six of my arms, and now you want one more?"
鲨鱼望着她  友善地笑着说
The shark looked at her with a friendly smile
"我并不想要一只胳膊"
and said, "I don't want one.
这回我想要剩下的全部  "但是为什么呢"  妮娜问
This time I want them all." "But why?" Nina asked.
鲨鱼接着回答说  "因为这就是交朋友的目的"
And the shark replied, "because that's what friends are for."
鲨鱼吃完了他的大餐
When the shark finished his meal,
他觉得非常悲伤和孤独
he felt very sad and lonely.
他想念和别人一起探索洞穴  一起堆砌沙堡
He missed having someone to explore caves, build castles,
一起游得飞快飞快的感觉
and swim really, really fast with.
他非常想念妮娜
He missed Nina very much.
所以他决定游去找寻下一个朋友
So he-- he swam away to find another friend.
贾登
Jayden?
你爸爸伤害过你么
Did your dad ever hurt you?
他现在还在伤害你么
Does he still hurt you?
我们不能让她回她家
We can't let her go back there.
放心吧  那不会发生的
That's not going to happen.
你今天做得很棒
You were pretty amazing today.
谢谢
Thank you.
麻烦再来点吧
More, please.
都再来点  都再来点
More for everyone. More of everything.
有谁想先吃点甜品么
Anyone, dessert first?
甜品  先来点甜品
Dessert? Dessert first?
不好意思  麻烦安静一下
Excuse me, excuse me.
大家好  大家好
Hello, hello. Hi.
不过我还是再用英文说一遍
But I'm going to say it in English
这样我就不用让自己再次出丑了
so I don't embarrass myself any more than I need to.
我想表达的就是
Uh, I just want to take a moment
谢谢你们  妈妈和爸爸
to say thank you, Mama, Pops.
我认为在座各位当中已经没人还把你们当作
I don't think anyone here thinks of you
养父母了
as just our foster parents.
我甚至不知道养父母是什么意思  因为在我眼中
I don't even know what that term means because to me,
你们就是我的父母
you're just Ma and Pa.
当我感谢你们接纳了我们所有人的时候
And I think I speak for everyone here when I say,
我相信其他人也是这么想的
thank you for taking us in.
感谢你们在我还是个对什么都害怕的愣头青时
For taking me in when I was just a punk kid
接纳了我
who was scared of everything.
当我孤单没有依靠的时候  你们收留了我
When I had no one else, you accepted me and you showed me
告诉了我
what it was like--
被爱是什么滋味
um, what it was like to be loved.
要不是你们  我们当中没有人能有今天的成绩
And none of us would be here if it weren't for you.
大家都看一看这个家庭有多美丽
Just look at this beautiful family you made.
都一起举杯向我们的国王和王后致敬
So let's all lift our glasses to our king and queen.
三十周年快乐
Happy 30th, you guys.
我生命中的一切美好都源于你们
Everything good in my life is because of you.
干杯
Salud.
Salud!
嫁给我好么
Will you marry me?
-你是认真的么  -当然
-You're serious?  -Yeah.
不能更认真了
I'm dead serious.
谁他妈又在打我们座机
Who the hell is calling on the land line?
你好
Hello?
我其实是  她的未婚夫
This is, uh, actually her, uh, fiance.
没错
Yeah.
如果这是关于她爸爸的消息
And if this is about her dad, it'd probably be best
你们最好告诉我  让我来转达
if you just let me relay the message.
我操
Oh, shit.
谁打的电话
Who was it?
是缓刑部门某个工作人员
That was someone from the probation department.
他们说你爸爸大概下个月
They said that your dad's probably going to
就要被释放了
get released next month.
我觉得我们需要好好聊一聊
I really think we need to talk through some of this stuff.
现在不是时候  梅森
Not right now, Mason.
我会好起来的  我只是
I'll be fine. I just--
我只是需要好好干活
I just need to work.
-你好  -你好
-Hey.  -Hi.
马库斯的鱼昨晚死了
Marcus' fish died last night.
什么
What?
他觉得路易斯跟这有关系
He thinks Luis had something to do with it.
真是这样么
Did he?
告诉我你没对马库斯的鱼做出什么事
Tell me you didn't do something to Marcus' fish.
-你在说啥  -路易斯  你快告诉我
-What?  -Luis, tell me.
可我真不知道你在说啥
I don't know what you're talking about.
我说的是真的
I swear!
马库斯  我很抱歉
I'm really sorry, Marcus.
不是路易斯干的
It wasn't Luis.
那已经没关系了
It don't matter.
如果你觉得没问题的话  我想自己待会儿
I'd like to be left alone, if that's cool with you.
好吧
OK.
你需要什么就尽管告诉我
Just let me know if you need anything.
你们见过贾登么
Have you guys seen Jayden?
杰斯  贾登在哪儿
Jess? Where's Jayden?
她爸爸昨晚来把她接走去过周末了
Oh, her dad showed up last night and took her on pass for the weekend.
-什么  -杰克还签字批准了
-What?  -Jack signed off on it.
你他妈是在跟我开玩笑吧
Are you fucking kidding me?
你怎么能让她走
How could you let her go?
简  等会儿我再回你电话好么
Uh, Jan, let me call you right back, OK?
她爸爸打了电话来  他道了歉
The man called. He apologized.
他说出了些私人的急事
He had a personal emergency.
可那根本不是关键点啊  杰克
That's not even the point, Jack.
你究竟有没有读我的报告
Did you read my report?
我当然读了  而且我也非常担心
Of course I did, and I was very concerned.
但当贾登的社工负责人问她时
But when Jayden's social worker asked her about it,
她说她爸爸从来都没有虐待过她
she said her father had never been abusive in any way.
她当然会这么说
Of course she said that.
她很害怕啊
She's fucking scared!
难道你们高中的时候他妈的没学过么
What the fuck did they teach you guys in grad school?
杰克  在她心目中她爸爸永远都在她身后
Jack, in her mind he is always right behind her,
监视着她的一举一动
watching her.
即便是她在睡觉  她在上厕所
When she is sleeping. When she is taking a shit.
甚至当她跟治疗师在一起时
When she is alone with her therapist,
她爸爸都会在那儿监控着她  随时准备开始一顿暴揍
he is right there watching her, ready to pounce.
你以为她会勇敢地走出阴影承认被虐待吗
And you just expect her to just come out and say it?
你们这些家伙他妈脑子都被屎吃了吗
Are you guys fucking stupid?
她到这里是来寻求帮助
Because she was here asking for help,
可你又把她送回了鲨鱼的血盆大口之中
and you just send her back to the fucking shark.
格蕾丝  我知道你很不高兴
I realize you're upset, Grace.
但对着我大吼大叫并不是有效的
But yelling at me isn't an effective form of
沟通方式
communication.
好
OK.
好的  杰克  我很抱歉
OK, Jack. Jack, I'm sorry.
在我们解决这件事之前  麻烦你取消周末假期
Please cancel the pass until we figure this out,
我了解她  我也了解她家里糟糕的情况
because I know her and I know that things are not good at home.
你怎么确定你真的了解她
And how do you know that?
就凭着她念的一个童话故事吗
Because she read you a children's story?
别他妈侮辱我  杰克
Don't fuck with me, Jack.
我每天从早到晚都在第一线跟这些孩子打交道
I am on the floor every day with those kids.
昨天晚上这个女孩就坐在我身边  哭得泪流满面
And last night, that girl sat next to me and she cried,
她尝试用她知道的唯一一种方式来告诉我
and she tried to tell me the only way that she knew how.
格蕾丝  你只是一个前线工作人员
Grace, you are a line staff.
试图解释每个人背后的悲剧不是你的职责
It's not your job to interpret tears.
接受过专业培训的治疗师才是负责这方面的
That's what our trained therapists are here for.
那些治疗师就他妈连狗屁都不懂
Then your trained therapists don't know shit.
她跟你明说她被她爸虐待了么
Did she tell you that she was being abused by her father?
她用不着明说
She didn't have to.
如果真要把那孩子从她亲生父亲身边带走的话
If I'm going to take that child away from her biological parent,
没错  她必须得明说
yes, she does.
真他妈荒唐
This is bullshit.
格蕾丝  我和这些孩子接触的时间可比你的年纪还大
Grace, I have been working with these kids longer than you've been alive.
而且我愿意为他们当中的每一个人鞠躬尽瘁
And there's not one of them that I wouldn't die for.
每当我凝望进他们一颗颗破碎的心时
I look into those broken eyes.
我都很想出去找到那个对他们造下这种孽的王八蛋
I want to go out and find the asshole who did that to them
把他们打个屁滚尿流
and beat the shit out of them.
但尽管我每天都如此挣扎
But although I feel that way every single day,
我却知道我不可能找到每一个罪人
I know I can't track down everyone who's hurt them.
我知道我没法治愈他们所有人
I know I can't heal all their wounds,
我也知道不能指控他们的父母是性犯罪施暴者
and I can't start accusing all their parents of being sexual offenders.
尤其是这种情况下  他们还是朋友的朋友  对吧杰克
Especially when they're friends of friends, right, Jack?
那我们没什么好讲的了  格蕾丝
We're finished here, Grace.
简
Jan--
萨米
Sam.
马库斯
Marcus?
马库斯你在吗
马库斯
Marcus?
你在路易斯的房间做什么
What are you doing in Luis' room?
噢  天啊
Oh, no.
路易斯  路易斯
Luis? Luis?
路易斯  你还好吗
Luis!
怎么了
What?
哦不
No.
我操  我操
Shit. Shit!
梅森  快来人啊
Mason! Somebody, anybody come!
快来帮帮我  路易斯
Help me! Luis!
路易斯  把你的枕头给我  快给我
Luis, I need your pillowcase right now. Give it to me.
快点啊
Quicker, please.
马库斯
Marcus?
马库斯  马库斯  求你看着我
Marcus. Marcus, please look at me.
马库斯  看着我  你会好起来的
Marcus, look at me. You're going to be OK.
我只需要你好好看着我
I just need you to look at me.
马库斯  看着我
Marcus, look at me.
为什么他妈的这么久都还没人来
What the fuck is taking so long?
我有了真正的朋友
Now I have a real friend.
我就叫你道里好了
I'm going to call you, uh, Dudley.
斯通医生
Dr. Stone--
布莱克・约翰逊  请拨号93
Blake Johnson, dial 93, please.
布莱克・约翰逊  拨号93
Blake Johnson, dial 93.
他们还是说不准
They still don't know anything.
我做不下去了
I can't do this.
格蕾丝
Grace.
嘿
Hey.
格蕾丝  你这是去哪儿
Grace, where are you going?
我做不下去了
I can't do this.
好吧  那我们走  我们回家
OK, let's go. Let's go.
我开车载你
I'll drive us home.
我不想回家
Don't want to go home.
我指的不是这件事
That's not what I'm talking about.
我知道今天糟糕透了
I know it's been a really fucked up day, OK?
梅森  你完全不知道我现在有多痛苦
Mason, you have no idea what I'm going through right now.
那就都告诉我  这才是解决问题的方式
Then tell me. That's how this works.
你先告诉我都发生了什么  我才可以牵着你的手
You talk to me about it so that I can take your hand
带着你熬过这些苦痛
and fucking walk through this shit with you.
毕竟这也是我的责任
That is what I signed up for, OK?
如果你一直紧锁心扉  我什么都帮不上
But I cannot do that if you won't let me in.
我说不出来
I can't.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你说对不起
You're sorry?
格蕾丝  你是认真的么
Grace, are you serious?
我可等了你这么久
I've been waiting for you for a really long time, and I
这等待中的每一分钟我都不会后悔
wouldn't take a second of it back
因为我实在是太他妈爱你了
because I love you so goddamn much, OK?
可我苦苦等了三年想让你告诉我
But I have been waiting for three years for you to tell me
为什么到现在你还是不肯信任我
why you still don't trust me.
我可是等了三年
I've been waiting for three years for you
我只是希望你能采取你对孩子们反反复复提出的建议
to just once take the advice that you give your kids
学会跟人分享自己脑海中
every fuckin' five minutes and learn to talk about
究竟在经历什么
what's going on inside your head.
为了我你也不肯这么做吗
You can't do that for me?
是什么都没关系  你都可以告诉我
Whatever it is, OK, just talk to me.
但我真的没办法做到
But I can't do this.
真的没办法
I can't--
我不能嫁给你
I can't marry you.
我不能怀上你的孩子
I can't have your baby.
我不能拥有这一切
I can't have any of it.
我做不到
I can't do it.
所以你想做些什么
So what do you want to do?
你要去堕胎么
Do you want to get an abortion?
我已经预约了
I already made the appointment.
你想做什么都行  满意了吧
Do whatever you want, OK?
因为我也受够了
Because I'm done.
孩子们根本不在乎它
Kids don't care nothing about it.
艾德  你想吃点吗
Ed, do you want some vittles today?
好的  奶奶
I do, Granny.
我醒来胃口很好  能吃下很多东西
I worked up a right smart appetite fetching sticks for old Duke.
这就是问题所在
Yes, that's the trouble around here.
动物正在掌管我们
The critters are taking over.
比利・梅给宠物喂了我的腌萝卜
Billie Mae has done made pets out of everything but my pickled turnips.
我们吃什么
What are we going to do for vittles?
等等  我记得附近开车的地方
Wait, I remember someplace to drive near--
你想干什么
What are you doing?
这也有点太过头了吧
That's a little extreme, don't you think?
你是疯了吗
Are you going crazy?
可能是吧
Probably.
当我还是你这么大的时候  我就不得不
When I was your age, I had to stand in a courtroom
跟一群陌生人一起站在公堂上  告诉他们
with a bunch of strangers and tell them all the ways
我爸爸是怎么虐待我的
that he abused me.
他是怎么打我的
What he hit me with.
他是怎么喝醉酒
How he got drunk.
他又是怎么强迫我跟他一块儿洗澡
How he forced me to take a shower with him.
还让我怀了孕
Got me pregnant.
我让他坐了牢
I sent him to prison.
我从没讲过这段经历
I didn't talk about it.
也没有想过这段经历
I didn't think about it.
一直到我遇见你
Until I met you.
可是我完全手足无措
And I don't know.
我身体里还有个宝宝呢  但是我不知道
I have a baby inside of me, and I don't know.
我真的不知道我正在做什么
I don't know what I'm doing.
我只是真的想帮助你
I was just trying to help you.
我的天啊
Oh my god.
他喜欢用腰带
He loves the belt.
真是毫无新意
It's such a cliche.
贾登  我们得对这做出应对
Jayden, we have to do something about this.
比方说在他还在睡觉的时候
Should go bash his face in with a baseball bat
用棒球棍打烂他的脸
while he's sleeping?
我觉得我们还是快点离开这儿
Uh, we should get out of here.
他睡得可死了
He'll sleep through anything.
好  我们得快点离开
OK. Now we should get out of here.
他们会问你很多的问题
They're going to ask you a lot of questions.
这个过程会很痛苦
It's going to be hard.
我会尽量不提到你拎着一根棒球棍
I'll try to leave out the part about you
就闯进了我们家
breaking into that house with a baseball bat.
谢谢
Thanks.
你会成为一个非常好的母亲
You're going to be a really good mom.
我告诉他这将是我最后一次回家
I told him this was going to be the last time I came home.
因为我再也受不了了
Because I'm not going to take his shit anymore.
当然他为此又发了一通大火
And that set him off, of course.
不过我一点也不在乎
But I didn't care.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我之前说的都不是真心话
I didn't mean what I said earlier.
只是这段时间我的生活一团糟
I'm just really messed up right now.
马库斯会好起来的
Marcus is going to get better.
我觉得我也会好起来的
I think I am too.
格蕾丝  我知道敞开心扉的对话很不容易
Grace, I know talking like this is really hard.
不过这已经是我们见的第四次面了  我希望你能
But this is our fourth session together, and I'd really like
努力地试一下  好么
you to try, OK?
可我不知道该说些什么
I don't really know what to say.
你爸爸一周内就要出狱了
Your dad's getting out of prison in a week.
你想聊聊这件事么
Do you want to talk about that?
好吧
OK.
你还好么
Are you OK?
留神看我身后的显示屏
Watch that monitor over my shoulder.
他大概就在  就在这儿
I think he's-- there we go.
看到他了
There he is.
别动  等一等
Stay with it. Hang on a second.
再等会
Hang on.
那是宝宝的心跳
That's-- that's the baby's heartbeat, man.
我的天啊
Oh, man.
你们仔细听好这个故事了  真是太他妈
So you need to get ready for this
难以置信了
because it's so fucking unbelievable.
这故事听起来可能很假  但我发誓是真事
It's going to seem fake, but I promise you it's not.
-格蕾丝可以作担保  -还得取决你有没有实事求是
-Grace will vouch for it.  -It depends if you tell it right.
绝对的实事求是
There is no way not to tell this right.
这整件事情简直就是讲故事人的春梦
It is a storyteller's wet dream.
-在说啥呢  -准备好听故事吧
-What?  -Get ready for this.
好的你正好赶上了  我从头开始讲
OK, just in time. I'm going to start at the beginning, OK.
行
OK.
三年前  我们这有这么一位姑娘叫做莱莎・格林
So three years ago, right, we have this girl here named Liza Green.
她十七岁  在当时比这儿所有孩子都要大
She's 17, older than everybody else on the unit at the time.
并不是我龌蹉的想法
And I don't mean this in a pervy way or anything,
但她真的很漂亮
but she's real pretty.
她确实是美极了
She was gorgeous.
所有的男孩子都喜欢她
All the guys on the unit want her,
只是她太忙了  不愿为任何一个人抽空
but she won't give any of them the time of day because she was busy.
-她总是在学习  -她也非常聪明
-She was always studying.  -She was very smart.
相当聪明
Mm-hmm. Really smart.
所以呢  在她到十八岁准备离开前两周
So two weeks before she turns 18 and leaves,
我们有了一位新房客
we get this new intake.
这男孩当时十五岁  他非常坚强
It's a 15-year-old guy. He's really tough.
他也非常沉默  不过他看起来拽拽的
He's really quiet. But he's cool.
他看起来很悠闲
He's just kind of like kicking back, checking out the scene.
而且我发誓他刚来的第一周  我还没听他说过一句话
And I swear I didn't hear him say a word the whole first week he was here.
但某天在社区会议上
But then one day we were doing community meeting,
我们问谁有通告的时候
and we ask for announcements.
这家伙举起了手
And this guy raises his hand.
他直接望着莱莎・格林说到  我知道你不认识我
And he looks directly at Liza Green and he says, I know you don't know me.
我也初来乍到
I just got here.
但我只想说我一直都在注意你
But I just want to say that I've been watching you.
我认为你是这破地方最有趣的东西了
I think you're the most interesting thing about this place,
而且我很伤心在你离开前没时间深入了解你
and I'm really sad I'm not going to get to know you before you leave.
我就想说这么多
I just wanted to tell you that.
真是个花花公子
What a pimp!
她怎么说呢  啥都没说
What did she say? Nothing.
啥都没说吗  当时真是太尴尬了
Nothing? It was so awkward.
完全受不了  太他妈尴尬了
Yeah, so fuckin' awkward I couldn't stand it.
然后她就离开了  一句话也没跟他说
And then she left, and never talked to him.
孩子们嘲笑了他一年
The kids teased him for like a year.
那感觉一定糟透了
Oh, that blows.
他一点都不在意  甚至一点没让他尴尬
No, he didn't give a shit. No, didn't even faze him.
就像是他有着别人没有的经验和知识
It was like he knew something everybody else didn't.
-这家伙是谁啊  -是马库斯
-Who is this guy?  -That was Marcus.
-什么  -我从没听过这个故事
-What?  -I never heard this story.
等等别着急  后面还更精彩
Oh, wait. It gets so much better.
仔细听接下来这段
Yeah. Yeah, so check this out.
某天早上我和格蕾丝准备去喝咖啡  我们走进咖啡店
Grace and I are getting coffee at Ronnie's this morning, and we walk in.
猜猜我们见到谁独自坐在那儿
And who do we see sitting there alone at a table?
就是马库斯
Marcus.
他还好吧
How's he doing? Oh!
他看起来好极了  他很不错
He looks great. He's so good.
穿着笔挺的衬衫
Buttoned-up shirt.
还啜着一杯卡布奇诺
He's sippin' on a cappuccino.
-马库斯也喝卡布奇诺吗  -显然是的
-Marcus drinks cappuccino?  -Yeah.
-我猜也是  -显然他现在会喝了
-Apparently.  -Yeah, I guess so.
然后我们跟他聊天
Apparently now he does.
问他近况如何
So we're talking to him and we're catching up.
他告诉我们他在水族馆找到了新工作
And he's telling us about his new job
赚到了多少小费
at the aquarium and how much he takes home in tips.
他现在开始申请下学期打算回去上学
And now he's going to start applying for classes next semester.
-天啊真棒  -是啊
-Oh my god!  -Yeah.
这种感觉真的太奇妙了
And it's weird because I'm like,
因为我从未见马库斯这么健谈
I have not heard Marcus talk this much ever, since I met him.
就在想这都是为什么呢  他是见到我们太高兴了呢
Like, what is the deal? Is he excited to see us?
还是对于什么事感到太紧张了
Is he nervous about something?
这时我才注意到桌上还有另外一杯卡布奇诺
And that's when I notice there's another cappuccino on the table
而且边上还有一只空椅子
and an empty chair next to him.
然后电影情节般的场景他妈的出现了
And then just like in the fucking movies,
厕所门突然打开  莱莎・格林走了出来
bathroom door flings open, out walks Liza Green.
-他们是在约会么  -这已经是他们第五次约会了
-They were on a date?  -It was like their fifth one.
-没错  -天啊
-Yes!  -Oh!
然后她一坐下来这家伙的脸就变得通红
As soon-- as soon as she sits down, dude just goes beet-red.
他觉得太尴尬了  他真是太可爱了
He's so embarrassed. Oh, it was so cute.
太他妈可爱了  我都快笑尿了
Oh, it was so fucking cute, I almost pissed my pants.
-看起来他们在一起很幸福  -真的太幸福
-Oh Jess, they look so happy together.  -So happy.
然后他们
And there's just--
又该干活了
Here we go.